AKI GAO

(703) 901-0568 | aki.gao@user1st.com | iknowht.ml | github.com/iknowhtml

Profile

I am a Software Engineer with a passion for technology and creating software that positively impact people and society. My areas of professional interests include the web, distributed systems and understanding the practices & habits of productive engineers, teams and organizations. I offer over three years of professional experience in software development using the JavaScript ecosystem and functional programming paradigms in Agile (Scrum) environments, including one year of professional experience in web & mobile accessibility.

Work Experience

User1st - Solutions Integrator, Washington, D.C.

January 2020 - Present

- Remediate websites to comply with accessibility standards using User1st's uRemediate™ platform for 15+ clients, including a large wireless network operator and a major railroad transporation company.
- Audit client websites and mobile applications for compliance with the WCAG 2.1 AA standard and Section 508 guidelines.
- Create internal tooling to automate tasks & improve productivity including:
 - A command-line tool built with Node.js & Puppeteer to automate website URL discovery and autogenerate web page screenshots to streamline and improve accuracy for time estimations for client websites.
 - A cross-browser extension built with the WebExtension browser API to inject runtime environment for client sites without the neccessary uRemediate™ snippet installed to replace unreliable tooling.

Alluminate - Full Stack Developer (Freelance), Washington, D.C.

November 2017 - June 2018

- Provided full stack development capabilities and expertise for work ranging from UI design to smart contract development.
- Designed and developed the company's homepage, as well as landing pages and a user portal for several products.
- Audited and tested Ethereum smart contracts for ERC-721 compatibility & general correctness, as well as bootstrapped metamask integration for front end clients and Ethereum test net infrastructure for smart contract deployments.

Booz Allen Hamilton - Technologist, Herndon, VA

May 2017 - November 2017

- Developed proof of concept Blockchain (Ethereum) applications for various government organizations, including an intra-departmental financial transaction system for the U.S. Treasury and a cryptographically-secured medical record system for the FDA.
- Worked across the stack from front end & back end development, in React and Express respectively, to the deployment pipelines to various cloud providers including AWS and Azure.

Skills

Languages:

JavaScript, Shell (Bash)

UX/UI & Front End Technologies:

Figma, HTML, CSS, JQuery, React, Redux

Back End Technologies:

Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL

Development and Testing Tools: Git, Yarn, Webpack, Babel, Jest, ESlint

Accessibility Tools & Technologies:

JAWS, NVDA, VoiceOver (iOS), TalkBack (Android), ARIA

DevOps & Infrastructure Technologies:

CircleCI, Docker, Kubernetes, Google Cloud Platform

Education

The University of Virginia: School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

August 2016

• B.S. Computer Engineering & B.S. Electrical Engineering